Hi again, for the next couple of months,
مرحباً مجدداً، خلال الشهرين القادمين،
I'll be your guide through this program.
سأكون مرشدك في هذا البرنامج.
I'm so excited to introduce the team that will be working with me to teach this course.
إنني متحمس جداً لتعريفك بالفريق الذي سيعمل معي في تدريس هذه الدورة.
First, I want to introduce Dana.
أولاً، أود تعريفك بـ"دانا".
She's teaming up with me on the first material you'll learn.
إنها تتعاون معي في تدريس أول مادة ستتعلمها.
Hello, I'm Dana.
مرحباً، أنا "دانا".
I'm an electrical engineer and computer scientist.
أنا مهندسة كهرباء وعالمة حاسوب.
I have many years experience working in industry to solve
لدي سنوات عديدة من الخبرة في العمل في الصناعة
problems and answer technical questions based on data.
لحل المشاكل والإجابة عن الأسئلة التقنية استناداً إلى البيانات.
Spreadsheets are one of my favorite tools for not only analyzing data but for
جداول البيانات هي إحدى أدواتي المفضلة، لا لتحليل البيانات فحسب،
creating charts and graphs to present my analysis clearly to clients and management.
وإنما لإنشاء الرسوم البيانية والمخططات لعرض تحليلاتي بوضوح للعملاء والإدارة.
I'm going to step you through the basics of spreadsheets.
سوف أعرض لك أساسيات جداول البيانات.
Once you learn these basics,
ما إن تتعلم هذه الأساسيات،
you'll be well-equipped to take it to the next level yourself.
سوف تكون مستعداً للانتقال إلى المستوى التالي بنفسك.
In the next section,
في الجزء التالي،
you'll be learning from Derek.
ستتعلم من "ديريك".
Derek , do you want to tell them a little bit about yourself?
"ديريك"، هل تريد أن تخبرهم عن نفسك قليلاً؟
I know we at Udacity are really excited
أعلم أننا في Udacity متحمسون جداً
to have you a part of the team leading this course.
لأن تكون جزءاً من الفريق الذي يدير هذه الدورة.
Thanks Josh. My name's Derek and I'm the CEO of Mode Analytics.
شكراً يا "جوش". اسمي "ديريك"، وأنا المدير التنفيذي لـ Mode Analytics.
An analytics platform that makes it easy to quickly turn SQL queries into
إنها منصة تحليلات تسهل عليك كيفية تحويل استعلامات SQL بسرعة
reports and dashboards that you can share across your company.
إلى تقارير ولوحات معلومات يمكنك مشاركتها في جميع أروقة شركتك.
I use Mode throughout this course,
أنا أستخدم Mode في هذه الدورة،
so you get a glimpse at some of its functionality.
بحيث ستحصل على لمحة عن خصائصها.
I've worked in analytics jobs throughout my career,
لقد عملت في وظائف تحليل البيانات خلال مسيرتي المهنية،
first in consulting then at tech companies like Facebook and Microsoft.
أولاً في تقديم الاستشارات ثم في شركات تقنية كبيرة مثل Facebook و Microsoft.
Everywhere I worked, I ended up teaching
في كل مكان عملتُ فيه، انتهى بي المطاف بتعليم
basic data analysis skills to up and coming analysts.
المهارات الأساسية في تحليل البيانات للمحللين المبتدئين.
And it really frustrated me that all the SQL content I could
وقد أحبطني أن جل محتوى الـ SQL الذي استطعتُ العثور عليه
This course incorporates everything I've learned from teaching SQL at previous jobs at
يدمج هذا المساق كل ما تعلمتُه من تعليم لغة SQL في وظائفي السابقة
Data Science boot-camps and its scale in other tutorials have produced. Hope you enjoy.
وفي معسكرات تعليم علم البيانات والدروس الأخرى التي أنتجتُها. أتمنى لكم وقتاً ممتعاً.
Then, you'll be learning data visualization and Tableau from Mat.
بعد ذلك، ستتعلم عرض البيانات المرئي وأداة Tableau من "مات".
Thanks. Hi there, I'm Mat.
شكراً. مرحباً، أنا "مات".
Back in the day, I was a physicist,
كنتُ في السابق عالم فيزياء
a neuroscientist and a data scientist.
وعالم أعصاب وعالم بيانات.
I've been working with data now for almost 15 years,
أعمل في مجال البيانات منذ نحو 15 عاماً،
starting my journey by simulating physical systems in Excel.
وقد بدأتُ رحلتي بمحاكاة النظم الفيزيائية في برنامج Excel.
In this program, I'll be covering one of the most important skills you'll need.
في هذا البرنامج، سأتناول واحدة من أهم المهارات التي ستحتاج إليها.
Sharing your results with others.
ألا وهي مشاركة نتائجك مع الآخرين.
We will be using Tableau.
سوف نستخدم أداة Tableau.
It's an industry standard application for creating
إنها تطبيق مطابق لمعايير الصناعة
amazing interactive visualizations. See you in class.
لإنشاء عروض مرئية تفاعليّة رائعة. أراك في الفصل.
And I'm Josh.
وأنا "جوش".
I'll be here to help you from start to graduation.
سأكون هنا لمساعدتك من البداية وحتى التخرّج.
I've been teaching introductory statistics courses and advanced graduate level classes
أنا أدرّس مقدمة في الإحصاء ودورات متقدمة بمستوى الدراسات العليا
aimed at computer programming and
مخصصة لبرمجة الحاسوب
data science at the University of Colorado Denver for the last few years.
وعلم البيانات في جامعة "كولورادو دينفر" خلال السنوات الماضية.
I also have held a number of industry positions ranging from marketing analyst,
كما شغلت وظائف عديدة ما بين محلل تسويق
to data scientist, to machine learning engineer, to biostatistician.
وعالم بيانات ومهندس تعلّم الآلة ثم خبير إحصاء حيوي.
Each of these positions was aimed at helping companies make the most of their data.
كل من هذه الوظائف كانت تهدف لمساعدة الشركات
Whether it be tracking and reporting,
سواء أكان التتبع ورفع التقارير
the success rates of drugs aimed to help people with cancer,
أو عن معدلات نجاح الأدوية التي تساعد المصابين بالسرطان،
or just building chat bots to bug my co-workers,
أو صنع روبوتات المحادثة لإزعاج زملائي في العمل.
I've always had a passion for data and teaching.
لطالما كان لدي شغف تجاه البيانات والتعليم.
I can't wait to be your guide on this adventure.
إنني متشوّق لأن أكون مرشدك في هذه المغامرة.